# Sai Srinath Josyula

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sai-srinath-josyula/ || http://www.saisrinathjosyula.com || https://github.com/sjosyul1

1265 E University Drive, App 1055, Tempe, Arizona, 85281. | 602-245-5945 | srinath.5893@gmail.com

### Career Summary:

Software Development professional with 2 years' experience in IT industry. I have hands-on experience on projects like Java, C#, Python Development, Django, Spring, Hibernate, AWS, Google Cloud, Full Stack Web development, Spark and Scala. Experience with REST API, SOAP API and Advanced Rest Client.

#### Education:

Master's in Information Technology

Arizona State University, AZ.

CGPA: 4/4

#### Related Coursework:

Software Engineering, Cloud Computing, Advanced SQL Techniques, System Administration of Unix, Networking, Algorithms and Data Structures, Analyzing Big Data, Advance Data Analytics.

### Skills and Abilities:

Languages: Java, Python, Scala, C#, SQL, Shell Scripting.

Web Technologies: HTML, XML, JavaScript, Hibernate, jQuery, Bootstrap, CSS, JSON, Django, Spring JSP, JSF, ASP.NET

Other Technologies: BigQuery, AWS, Spark GraphX, Spark Streaming, Spark SQL, Ambari, HDFS.

## **Projects**

- Built a Meetup portal for ASU polytechnic campus using which students and faculty can organize meetings and share their knowledge. Technologies used JAVA, JDBC, Servlets, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Built a fully functional portal for Photo-voltaic Module certification using Python, Django framework. Used MSSQL as database and implemented Stored procedures, Cursors, Triggers, Views, Dynamic SQL. Followed Agile methodology.
- Twitter-Review Analysis: Main aim is to provide review analysis of place, food, events etc. through charts. Used Django to provide user interface. Deployed application on Google App Engine, used BigQuery to store Tweets. Google Data Studio to Visualize data. Technologies: Python, Django, Google App Engine, BigQuery, Google Data Studio.
- Analyzed Big data on cloud. Main aim of the project was to find duplication of questions from Quora question pairs. I have
  Used Scala for analyzing data and created Spark clusters on AWS. Data Visualization was done using Amazon Quick Sight
  and Tableau.
- Administration of Hadoop and Spark Cluster on VM using Hortonworks Distributions. I have setup Hadoop ecosystem on a 4-node cluster on VMware workstation 14 pro. Using Ambari added HDFS, Pig, Hive, MapReduce 2, Spark, Zookeeper and Squoop.
- Multi-Threaded webserver: Main aim is to handle multiple request at once. Deployed the application on AWS. I have used Wireshark to capture network traffic. Technologies: Java, AWS, Networking.
- SpamHam Analysis: Main aim of the project was if an email is spam or ham using Spark ML techniques. Built ML pipeline using Spark libraries. Technologies used are Spark, Scala, Spark ML
- Hosmer Medical Analysis: Using ML pipeline Techniques analyzed if a patient had breast cancer. Tech: Spark, Scala.

### Work Experience: (Software Engineer)

## INTERNSHIP: Edgenuity, Scottsdale

**Sep 2018 – Dec 2018** 

Jan 2017- Dec 2018

• Developing a software which can create a development environment for Edgenuity employees. User can login and self-configure the software's required for his work and monitor the progress on the dashboard. Languages: C #, Shell Scripting, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, MVC, JS, React JS, Bootstrap, Database.

# INTERNSHIP: Infosys, Mysore.

Dec 2014 - April 2015

• Trained in Infosys, Mysore for 5 months on Java, Database Management, Software Engineering, HTML5, CSS3, Java Scripting and Finacle. Completed a Full Stack Web Development project as a part of the training.

#### **Infosys and EdgeVerve:**

Apr 2015 - Dec 2016

- Part of Edge Verve, Finacle. It is a banking product developed by Infosys. My work involved development of Finacle Treasury
  enhancements using JAVA as programming language, moving configuration of app sever to database which enabled FT
  manager.
- Support of custodian account for securities Buy/Sell, Repo and Equity/MF deals and quick setup which automates the setup of various screens like scheme details, swift messages. Programming language is JAVA. Followed Agile methodologies and Projects were completely customer driven. Worked on Unix and Database for an application called Finacle Treasury.

#### **Impetus (Software Engineer)**

Jan 2019 - Present

• My current role is giving me opportunity to work on MapReduce, Spark, Kafka, HBase, Hive, Oozie and Zookeeper on MapR cluster. I'm using Java and Scala as programming language.